# JINGYU WANG

# **Software Engineer**

A professional and versatile computer science graduate with full-stack experience in developing Android and Rail applications. Lectured twice a week in the open lab of Department of Computer Science of Saint Joseph's University. Instructed and motivated over 60 students by tutoring and advising.

# **EDUCATION**

Saint Joseph's University, Philadelphia, PA M.S. in Computer Science 2015-2017 Cumulative GPA: 3.70/4.00 Rank top 5% 2007-2011 B.E. in Civil Engineering Nanjing University of Technology, Nanjing, China Cumulative GPA: 3.50/4.00 Rank top 5%

# **AWARDS**

Member of ACM Apr 2017

Member of Upsilon Pi Epsilon Apr 2017

(The international computer honor society based on superior achievements and scholarship rating)

**Outstanding Undergraduates Awards** May 2011

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Teaching Assistant** Saint Joseph's University Sep 2017-

- Lectured and supervised computer open labs weekly and reported on students' progress.
- Helped professor to design project.
- Graded course Software Engineering assignments by using JUnit Test Framework.

**Director of the Computer** Jiangsu Meicheng Architectural & Planning Jul 2012- Feb 2015 **Network & Information Center** Design Institute CO.,LTD

- Monitored, troubleshot and maintained company's network system and the website.
- · Cooperated with other departments.
- Directed the utilization of professional software.

#### RELEVENT PROJECT

#### **Full-Stack Android Project**

Sep 2016- Dec 2016

- Designed and built a social app powered by a NoSQL database focusing on people who work out.
- Implemented Agile software development.
- Users include trainers and students. Trainers can post training classes, create chatting group. Students can search class by rating, price and distance. Both of them are able to search, comment
- Involved Google Map API to show the path and distance from user to the work out place.
- Designed a customized ListView widget to display the list of "my friends" and live chatting UI.

#### Full-Stack Ruby on Rails Project

Sep 2016- Dec 2016

- Implemented an interactive and responsive front-end that communicates with a SQLite database, enabling the struggling students to search and send messages to the campus tutors based on the reviews conveniently and to help them succeed in the coursework.
- Designed and implemented a dedicated administrator's page for maintaining users and ads.
- Designed and built a highly normalized relational database schema, ERD diagrams and wrote complex SQL queries
- Received 100% positive feedback from professors, students and campus tutors who used the app on a daily basis.

#### **Contact Info:**



267-760-7380



JingyuWang@gmail.com 3901 Conshohocken Ave, Philadelphia, PA 19131



www.linkedin.com/in/jingyu88

### **Personal Skills**

Attention to detail Problem solving Planning strategically Team leader and team player Excellent organizational skill

# Language

Java C/C++ Pvthon HTML/PHP MySQL Ruby

### Technical Skills

Ruby on Rails Linux Git SQL Hadoop Firebase MapReduce Platform

Android SDK

# **Expertise**

Data Structure Design & Analysis of Algorithm Database Big Data Mobile platforms Software Eng.

# **Software**

Visual Studio Android Studio Git **Eclipse** IntelliJ IDEA Notepad++